<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NLP on Eric Chandler</title>
    <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/tags/nlp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NLP on Eric Chandler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:29:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eric-mc2.github.io/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Public Safety News Analysis (Engineering)</title>
      <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/qjn-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 16:29:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/qjn-methods/</guid>
      <description>This post describes the technical implementation of the public safety news analysis.&#xA;Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented a LOT more and need to update the writeup!&#xA;Training Data News articles: I labeled an independent sample to train each task.&#xA;Chicago streets network: I enumerated all blocks and intersections and spatially joined these with community area boundaries. I used these {location -&amp;gt; community area} mappings as synthetic data to train the classifier.&#xA;Architecture Article Classifier: This is an off-the-shelf uninitialized binary text classification model.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Safety News Analysis</title>
      <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/qjn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:34:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/qjn/</guid>
      <description>Introduction According to Pew Research, crime is the second-most watched news topic besides weather. Over three quarters of U.S. adults say get news about crime sometimes or often.1 How accurate is this information? How does it affect public perceptions on crime? And how, ultimately, does that affect public safety conversations, economic behaviors, and social good.&#xA;Decades of social science research have shown the importance of news coverage in shaping our world views.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Social Structure of Private Donations to Police</title>
      <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/publications/shachter-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eric-mc2.github.io/publications/shachter-structure/</guid>
      <description>How does private money flow to police departments, and what do these donations reveal about power and accountability in public safety?&#xA;Although previous studies have focused on police foundations moving tens of millions of dollars, the authors’ research uncovers a broader, more complex ecosystem of private police financial support. Using a unique data license from GuideStar Candid—all nonprofit organization tax returns from 2014 to 2019—the authors describe a larger and integrated world of organizations moving private money to police.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
