<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Eric Chandler</title>
    <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Eric Chandler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eric-mc2.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Texas School Reading Scores</title>
      <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/3rd-grade-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/3rd-grade-reading/</guid>
      <description>View app on Observable Cloud&#xA;This was an interview take-home project. The prompt was &amp;ldquo;Make a dashboard for a school district leader, comparing standardized test scores (3rd grade reading level meets grade level) to household income and poverty at the zip code level. Don&amp;rsquo;t do statistical analysis.&amp;rdquo; Links were provided to school-level test scores, school locations, and zip-level Census ACS data.&#xA;Features Search by zip or school district name. Find similar communities based on economic factors (k nearest neighbors).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>527 Network Explorer</title>
      <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/527-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/527-explorer/</guid>
      <description>527 Explorer Network visualization of ProPublica&amp;rsquo;s 527 Explorer, built with Observable Framework.&#xA;Demo (so far &amp;hellip;)&#xA;Why make this? This project is in part, an extension of my prior research into nonprofit donations networks.&#xA;I would like to write my own opinionated d3.js layout that deals with the scale-free and core-periphery characteristics of these networks. Having code to query and visualize a donations dataset was a first step.&#xA;I also have ambitions to create better looking interactive visualizations, and was curious by the interactivity provided by Observable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Democrats Really Support Public Transit?</title>
      <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/dnc-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 10:47:51 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/dnc-effect/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I fumbled an interview question on statistical modeling. That hurt my pride, so I decided to take on a little modeling project.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ll follow the standard economic practice of creating a quasi-experiment out of a policy implemented with some randomness.&#xA;I exploit the exogeneous shock of the 2024 Democratic National Convention in Chicago, (ie. the addition of tens of thousands of politically active Democrats) to test whether a statistically significant change in public transit is observed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Transit Ridership Panel</title>
      <link>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/transit-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 11:07:59 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eric-mc2.github.io/projects/transit-panel/</guid>
      <description>This page describes the steps I took to create a panel dataset of ridership across different Chicago transit systems. I did this to practice econometric modeling.&#xA;Transit modes and data sources Included modes&#xA;Train, Bus, Rideshares - from the City of Chicago (used Socrata API and sodapy python package) Bikeshares aka Divvy Bikes - from Lyft (used s3fs python package to access public Amazon S3 bucket) Excluded modes&#xA;Metra commuter rail (public data is available but too coarsely aggregated) Pace city-suburb bus link (have not checked availability) Walking / Biking (vendored data is available &amp;ndash; ie cell phone location data &amp;ndash; but would be hard to isolate from other transit modalities) Driving (public data is available &amp;ndash; ie road segment usage &amp;ndash; but haven&amp;rsquo;t seriously looked yet) Extra data</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
